以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好吧，让我重新开始
okay let me start again
感谢Rao教授的帮助
thanks for helping with Professor Rao
并在最后两个实验室工作
and working on the labs the last two
次我说实验室真的
times I was saying the labs were really
为他的班级，这是90分钟
for his class which is 90 minutes so
我们有点没时间了
that we were kind of running out of time
只是回答你所知道的那些问题
just answering those questions you know
让系统说OK继续下去
getting the system to say ok keep going
无论如何，他会发展那些和我
anyway he's going to develop those and I
认为这样会有好事
think there'll be a good thing so
实际上我和第二个实验室一样
actually the second lab I was as I was
看着它我在想数学
watching it I I was thinking of a math
问题，我可以就此向您汇报
question and may I report to you on that
数学问题所以记得实验室是
math question so remember the lab was
完成矩阵你有一些
completing a matrix you've got some
条目，你可以放入任何其他
entries and you can put in any other
在其他位置和条目
entries in the other positions and the
问题是，你能完成它的
question was can you complete it to a
排名一个矩阵，所以这里是什么
rank one matrix and so what was here's
我的问题是什么立场是好的
my question what positions are ok and
你可能不会是什么位置
what positions could you maybe not be
能够完成一级矩阵
able to complete to a rank one matrix
例子是最好的所以我是
examples are the best okay so so I'm
看这个问题，好吧
looking at this question here ok so
假设我正在寻找排名第一
suppose I I'm looking for a rank one
X列y转置形式的矩阵
matrix of the form X column y transpose
或UV转置我想我们就是那些
or UV transpose I guess we're those are
我们用来进行UV转置的字母
the letters we're used to UV transpose
这当然意味着每个IJ
and that means of course that a IJ each
一个IJ
a IJ
是UI时间VJ正确所以我们得到了我们
is UI times VJ right so we've got we're
能够选择我们有M使用让我问
able to choose we have M used let me ask
我可以提出一个问题，让我来吧
a question could I complete so let me
取m等于n等于3所以3乘3矩阵
take m equal n equals 3 so 3 by 3 matrix
我会给你我的罪减1
I'm gonna give you my sin minus 1 which
是3加3减去15个职位和
is 3 plus 3 minus 1 5 positions and
假设I+4并给出一些非零值
suppose I + 4 and give some non zeros in
其中5个职位
which 5 positions
所以Y是数字M加n的地方
so Y is where is that number M plus n
因为我有，所以减去1来
minus 1 coming from well because I have
m使用，我有羡慕对于等级1
M use and I have envies for for Rank 1
矩阵我从1变为MJ从1变为1
matrix I goes from 1 to M J goes from 1
到N所以我有M+n，但显然有
to N so I have M + n but obviously there
我可以让我可以要求
I could I could make I could require the
首先你是一个1，换句话说
first you to be a 1 in other words when
我将那些乘以一度
I'm multiplying those there's one degree
那种重复的自由
of freedom that that is sort of repeated
在这里，因为如果我只是给你
here because if I'm just given you if
无论如何，我只是给你一个
I'm just give just in the one anyway you
看到我可以重新调整使用量
see it that that I can rescale the use
所以第一个u是1和那个
so that the first u is a 1 and and that
离开我M+n-1所以我可以给你
leaves me M + n - 1 so could I give you
这五个数字也可以
these five numbers and could you
完成到一级矩阵所以
complete that to a rank one matrix so
那些是非零的，为什么我说没有
those are non zeros why do I say none
零，因为如果那个号码发生了
zeros because if that number happened to
是零，我有坏
be a zero I'd have bad
如果我开了一个和我
if I prescribed that one and I
规定它为零然后如果每个
prescribed it to be zero then if every
列必须是其中的倍数
column has to be a multiple of that
列这些都必须为零
column these would all have to be zero
所以我不希望我能够
so I don't want that I want to be able
因此，规定五个数字
to prescribe five numbers and therefore
他们最好不要零也好
they better better not be zero okay
你能完成那份工作吗？
could you complete the job with that
我认为你可以选择五个职位
choice of of five positions I think you
可能因为你会如何决定
could because how would you decide on
这个数字我至少是一种方式
that number well I'm at least one way to
看看它是什么数字
look at it is what would that number be
那就是这个号码
there so this is that number would be
选择那里只有一个选择
chosen there be one and only one choice
因为这将给予排名第一
for that that would give rank one in
事实上，2比2的决定因素
fact that little 2 by 2 determinant
必须是0好写所有
would have to be 0 well write the all
所有列都应该是行
the rows all the columns are supposed to
是所有行的一列的倍数
be multiples of one column all the rows
应该是一行的倍数
are supposed to be multiples of one row
所有这两个人都是我们的等级1
all the two by twos are our rank 1
他们都是2并且排名第2
they're all and rank 1 for a 2 by 2
意味着决定因素0所以我会知道什么
means determinant 0 so I would know what
一个必须是数字将
that one had to be that number would
必须是1121211
have to be a 1 2 times a 2 1 over a 1 1
那是因为我必须得到每2个
that's because I have to get a every 2
如果我，那么2个行列式必须为0
by 2 determinant has to be 0 here if I
想要排名1我不能忍受任何两个
want Rank 1 I can't stand any two by
两个是可逆的
twos that are that are invertible
矩阵因此所有决定因素都必须如此
matrices so all the determinants have to
是0
be 0
好的，当然还有这3个数字
ok and of course then these 3 numbers
我会允许我填写那3个
would allow me to fill in there those 3
数字将允许我填补
numbers would allow me to fill that
我可以填写那3个数字
those 3 numbers well I may fill that
它很容易，所以我可以看到
it'd be easy easy so that I can see that
这些是有效的5个职位
those are 5 positions that work
现在给我五个不会的职位
now give me five positions that won't
工作所以这很好，现在检查我
work so this is good this is check now I
想要一个我无法工作的地方
want one that where I can't make it work
所以让我给那个数字，这个数字
so let me give that number that number
好吧好吧我正在寻找一些东西
okay well so I'm looking for something
失败的一组职位失败了
that fails a set of positions that fails
然后我想能够测试吗
and then I want to be able to test does
这组职位适合任何非
the set of positions work for any non
零或它不能正常工作所以我想要
zeros or does it not work okay so I want
互相了解我在寻找什么
to get one another what am I looking for
这是另一个有效的
here another a different one that works
好吧那么还有什么可以分开的
okay so what else would work apart from
让我们看看我想我接受那一个
that let's see I suppose I take that one
那我在那个位置怎么样？
now what about that position there I
不能选择一个合适的，我必须
must not choose that one right I must
不要选择那个，因为那会
not choose that one because that would
完成两个两个，如果我给了
complete a two by two and if if I gave
错误的数字是决定因素
the wrong numbers the determinant
不会是零，我会失败
wouldn't be zero and I would be failed
所以我不能给我那个位置
so I must not give that position maybe I
也许我可以给那个位置
could give that position maybe I could
如果我有这些，那么给这个怎么样
give this one how's that if I had those
五，我能完成它
five would I be able to complete it
看起来不错，反正它看起来好让的
looks good anyway it looks good let's
看看我将如何完成它
see how would I go about completing that
让我们看看我能不知道那是什么
let's see I could I would know what that
数字必须来自这两个两个
number had to be from this two by two
从这两个两个我想知道
from this two by two I would know that
这先生的数字现在这个和
number from this sir where now this and
这个和现在这不是什么好事
this and this now that's not any good
我现在该怎么办才能得到如何
what do I do now to get how would I get
这个号码
this number
哦好吧我想我必须这样才能搞定
oh okay I guess I have to use so to get
这将完成那个或两个
this would complete that or this two by
两个哦是的没关系没问题
two oh yeah okay no problem
永远不会完成那个权利
that would never complete that one right
但是这个我不认为我能得到
but this one I don't think I can get
我马上就知道了
immediately but I can get it once I know
这些显然我可以得到那个我
these then obviously I can get that I
可以做到这一点，所以我必须
can get that right so I have to
这是一种很好的组合
it's a sort of nice combinatorial
五个职位的问题
problem which which five positions will
工作哪五个五个不行
work which five which five will not work
我怎么说，或者当然是这样的
how do I tell so or of course that's for
3x3是的，所以让我有一个更大的
3x3 yeah so let me I had a like a bigger
让我让我升级到4x4
example let me let me move up to 4x4 so
所以现在这里有我的想法
so now here's here comes the idea that I
昨晚从数学教授那里学到的
learned last night from a math professor
谁做组合s--所以这些
who does combinatoric s-- so these
做他们认识的组合学的人
people who do combinatorics they've know
我们其他人没有的东西
stuff that the rest of us don't
好的，所以这是他的观点
okay so here's the his his view is to
采取有这些将是行一二
take have these would be rows one two
三，我可能会添加另一行让我
three I may I may add another row let me
做一个4x4和这些将是一个列
do a 4x4 and these would be columns one
二三四
two three four
好吧，现在我正在寻找七个如此
okay now I'm looking for seven so so if
我订了一个条目，我会把它放在边缘
I prescribed an entry I'll put in a edge
他们之间让我让我炒作炒作
between them so let me let me hype hype
这个最多4x4是啊是的，这是一个很好的
this one up to 4x4 yeah yeah it's a good
其实我只是画这幅画
one actually I'll just draw this picture
所以假设我开了一个哦
so suppose I prescribed the one one oh
是的，在这里，我会告诉你什么
yeah and over here I'll show you what
我这样做是为了让我加入一个
I've done so that I'm putting in the one
一个位置我正在寻找七个权利
one position I'm looking for seven right
四加四减一七数
four plus four minus one seven numbers
好的
okay
然后我会把这个放在第二行
then I'll put in this is Row two column
一排两列的一个，这将是
one row two column one that would be
那时我会把两到四个放进去
there then I'll put in a two to four so
那将是第二排第四列
that would be Row two column four then
我会在3到4，这样
I'll put in a three to four so that
将是第3行第4列，最后我会
would be Row 3 column 4 and finally I'll
让我们看看我做了多少
put in let's see so how many have I done
一两三四我必须得到
one two three four and I've got to get
多达七个规定7
up to seven prescribe seven
好吧，让我，我的意思是我会放脚
well let me I mean I'll put a foot
Mauryan还好，我给了第四排
Mauryan okay so so on row four I gave
两个三个和四个我输入了这个
two three and four and did I put in this
一个是的我做得很好所以我现在
one yes I did okay well so I've now
我可以订七七个号码
prescribed seven seven numbers could I
完成矩阵以对一个矩阵进行排名
complete the matrix to rank one matrix
你是怎么看待数学问题的
how you see the math question if I'm
在那里我有7个职位
given seven positions there I can this
是另一种看待同样的方式
is another way to look at the same
图片这是我放在一边的
picture this is I put in an edge for
每一个X所以，如果我有七个X，我就得到了
every X so if I have seven X's I've got
七个边缘，这称为a
seven edges and and this is called a
二分图所以它是我得到的图
bipartite graph so it's a graph I've got
四个节点这里有四个节点，所以我
four nodes here four nodes here so I
有八个节点
have eight nodes
它是一个二分图，因为它
it's a bipartite graph because the the
节点我有超过节点的一部分
nodes I have one part of nodes over
这里有一部分节点是二分的
there one part of nodes here bipartite
意思是两个部分，所以行给我一个
means two parts so the rows give me one
列给我的部分边缘
part of the edges the columns give me
边缘的另一部分和所有
the other part of the edges and all the
在我不是的部分之间进行连接
connections go between the parts I'm not
我没有从行中的任意行
I don't have any lines from from a row
因为所有的代码都是
to a row because all the whole code is
这告诉我那些在哪里
that this tells me what where those
七个职位现在好，我只是
seven positions are okay now I'm just
要问你我可以完成
going to ask you can I complete the
我可以完成矩阵图
graph can I complete the matrix can I
完整的秩一个矩阵有什么好
complete rank one matrix there okay what
你是否认为如此真实
do you think so the and the real
问题是什么是什么规则
question is what's the rule what what
什么是我什么时候能不能看到的
what's the how can I see when I can't
完成矩阵得到的东西在
complete the matrix something gets in
这里的道路是神在路上的样子
the way here what God in the way was
这个2x2
this 2x2
实际上我问过这个问题
and actually I asked the question on
电子邮件是我可以随时完成它
email is it can I always complete it
是啊
yeah
所以，让我这就是我的问题
so let me that would be the question I
可以问你我可以随时完成
could ask you can I always complete the
图你完成矩阵有
graph you complete the matrix to have
当我没有遇到时排名第1
Rank 1 when there when I don't run into
这就是我要避免的一切
this is that all I have to avoid a
两个两个我在哪里给了三个
two-by-two where I've given three where
我给了所有四个参赛作品，所以是的
I'm given all four entries so yeah here
这个II能够如此完成
this I I was able to complete yeah so so
抱歉，如果我得到了，我们就做一个
sorry duh let's do one if I if I'm given
那些条目，也许还有其他一些我
those entries and maybe some others I
总共猜七是失败了
guess seven altogether that's a failure
对我，如果我不能处方任何非
right I if I can't prescribe any non
因为这七个职位的零
zeros in those seven positions because
如果我可能会开出任何非零值
if I prescribe any non zeros I probably
我不会有零决定因素
won't have a zero determinant here I
不会对该列排名第一
won't have rank one that that column
将不会是那个的倍数
will be will not be a multiple of that
无论我在这里做什么，我都搞砸了
column whatever I do here I've screwed
已经这样就失败了
up already so that's a fail okay right
我该如何让我拍摄这张照片
and how do I let me take that picture
然后把它变成这张照片
and and turn it into this picture
所以行列，所以如果我采取这七个
so rows columns so if I take these seven
那是第1排1234所以第1排去了
that's Row 1 Row 1 2 3 4 so Row 1 goes
到1和2行2到1和2行3
to 1 and 2 Row 2 goes to 1 and 2 Row 3
转到4，第4行转到3和4
goes to 4 and Row 4 goes to 3 and 4
这是一个失败，我怎么知道它
that's a failure and how do I know it's
一个失败我想现在拿出来
a failure I want to now come up with the
答案拿出答案，如果我
answer come up with the answer so if I
给任何7个职位或任何M加n
give any 7 positions or any M plus n
减去我可以创造的1个位置
minus 1 positions like that I can create
像这样的图只是跟随
a graph like that just following the
你看到那些的规则
rule that you saw those
七个位置给了我七个优势
seven positions gave me seven edges in
我的图表，它是一个二分图
my graph and it's a bipartite graph
因为每个边缘都来自这个部分
because every edge goes from this part
到这一部分，这是一个失败
over to this part and that's a failure
它失败的原因是
and the reason it's a failure is the
我失败的原因是我有
reason it's a failure is that I have
这是一个循环，如果我穿过对面
here a cycle if I go across down across
我回来了，我开始了
down I come back where I started that
将是一个循环等于失败大
would be a cycle equals failure big
每个人都看到我不能给这四个
everybody sees I can't give these four
数字一般我都要马宁
numbers generally I would have to manin
你们三个我没有任何自由
you three I don't have any freedom left
那第四个和看的方式
where that fourth one and the way to see
在这张照片中就是那样的
that in this picture is that that's that
这是一个循环，所以这里是
there's a cycle so here's the
教授那个组合的东西
combinatoric thing that that Professor
波斯纳COFF告诉我昨晚你
Posner COFF told me about last night you
如果和，可以完成一级矩阵
can complete to a rank one matrix if and
只有在没有循环的情况下才是这样的
only if no cycles so that was a that was
这是我刚刚回答的问题
a that's a just answered my question
完美
perfectly
这个是我可以完成的一个
this one is one where I can complete and
它有一个循环周期意味着你来了
it's got a cycle cycle meaning you come
回到你开始的地方，但是我
back to where you started but so I I
想到也许这样我对他的问题
thought maybe so my question to him
你可以随时完成它
which was was can you always complete it
如果在途中没有两个两个
if there are no two by twos in the way
他的回答告诉我，也许是
and his answers told me that maybe the
两个两个可以没关系但是那里
two by twos could be okay but there
可能是一个更长周期的更大周期
could be a bigger cycle a longer cycle
那会搞砸你让我闭上
that would screw you up so let me close
与那种类型的例子
with with an example of that sort
所以这将再次失败
so this is going to be fail again
但是没有2x2在其他方面负责
but but no 2x2 is responsible in other
言语它会失败我将无法做到
words it's gonna fail I won't be able to
完成此矩阵即使如此有
complete this matrix even so there
是不是任何完成的两个由两个2乘
aren't any completed two by twos a 2 by
a2by2我立即知道失败了
a 2 by 2 I knew immediately was failure
所以，让我看看我能做到这一点没关系
so let me see if I can do that okay okay
所以这是一个失败的行12这是行
so here's a failure Row 1 2 this is rows
1234这是列1234和
1 2 3 4 and this is columns 1 2 3 4 and
我想我会在那里得到一个
I think I'm gonna have a 1 given there
是的我以前开始这样做了
and yeah I sort of started this before
2到1和4＆3到4和4
and 2 goes to 1 & 4 & 3 goes to 4 and 4
去那个安全的赌注现在我好了
goes to that safe bet okay now I've only
投入245我允许7但我
put in 2 4 5 and I'm allowed 7 but I
想我已经在这里出事所以让
think I'm already in trouble here so let
我让我得出这样的照片在这个如此
me let me draw this picture for this so
这是行1234，这是列
this is rows 1 2 3 4 and this is columns
1234现在我怎么办？
1 2 3 4 and now what if I I've
规定一个我知道的
prescribed that one I know that goes
从哦，我忘记了正确的方法
from oh my forgotten the right way to do
照片我的bybite我的二分
the picture my by.bite my bipartite
图不是应该如此
graph wasn't what it should have been so
1234现在我好了
that 1 2 3 4 okay now I'm going to do
的二分图图像即
the the bipartite graph picture that
跟这张照片一样1211221
goes with this picture so 1 2 1 1 2 2 1
224我要做什么
2 2 4 what I'm gonna do
我只想说一下我要做的事情
let me just say what I'm gonna do I'm
在这里创造一个长度的循环
gonna create a cycle over here of length
6长度为4的循环是我得到的
6 a cycle of length 4 is what I got from
一个2乘2乘2乘2给我一个
a 2 by 2 by 2 by 2 that took me 1 one
回来的另一个回来
way back another back another back
另一个我完成了一个循环，我回来了
another I completed a cycle I came back
到我开始的地方
to where I started
现在我想要一个只有四条边
with just four edges now I want a
用6完成一个完整的循环
complete one complete a cycle with 6
边缘，以便让我，让我把它收回去了
edges so let me let me draw it in the
那么现在我要放了
picture here then now I'm going to put
一个边缘从四个回到一个所以11
an edge from four back to one so so 1 1
21124221224如果我有任何东西
2 1 1 2 4 2 2 1 2 2 4 if I got any yeah
我想12
I think 1 2
该死的我不想要一个短暂的周期
goddamn I didn't want a short cycle I
如果你想要一个更大更长的周期让我
want a bigger longer cycle let me if you
让我得到这样的事情，所以224是
let me get the darn thing so 2 2 4 is
不是我想要的所以我在这里开始一个循环
not what I want so I here start a cycle
OK去的地方回头去的地方去
ok go somewhere go back go somewhere go
回到某个地方回去吧我
back go somewhere go back now there I
得到它长度6长度6所以现在让我
got it length 6 length 6 so now let me
把X放在他们现在属于的地方
put the X's in where they belong now so
一个连接到一个和四个
one is connected to one and four that's
右2连接到2和43不连接
right 2 is connected to 2 and 4 3 is not
连接到任何人让我们放
connected to anybody let's let's put
一个在和4被连接到1和
that one in and 4 is connected to 1 and
24连接到1和2
2 4 is connected to 1 & 2
好吧，我相信这个我相信那张照片
ok I believe this I believe that picture
现在我的主张就是这张照片
goes with that picture now my claim is
那里没有没有2
that there are no there there's no 2 by
2在这里立即显示我
2 in here that shows me immediately
失败但我会失败我无法生存
failure but I will fail I can't live
接着就，随即
with that
那些看起来像8的人
with those that looks like 8
抱歉，我只想要七个，所以我
sorry I've got I only want seven so I
我应该对不起三四
just shall I just take sorry three four
而且不应该有正确的好吗
and that shouldn't be there right okay
谢谢
thanks
好吧，你看，我不是一个组合
all right you see I'm not a combinatoric
人，但它是如此美丽有
person but it's so beautiful to have the
灵感将图片转换为
inspiration to convert that picture to
这张照片然后意识到了
this picture and then realize that a
这张照片中的问题是一个循环
problem in this picture is a cycle in
这张照片就是整个信息
this picture that's the whole message
这就是我的时候的全部信息
that's the whole message that when I'm
看这里一个循环意味着我就是我
looking here a cycle means that I'm I've
建立在一个随机的要求
built in a requirement which random
非零不会满足所以你看到了
non-zeros won't satisfy so you see that
无论如何你看到周期1123456
anyway you see the cycle 1 1 2 3 4 5 6
是的，所以那里有一个循环
yeah yeah so there's a cycle there so
不知怎的，那些6X是我们的
somehow those 6 X's whichever they are I
猜不到除了23遮阳板3所以我可以
guess not all but 2 3 visor 3 so I could
我可以带走这一部分
take I could take away this part of the
图表，只有3和3和那里
graph and just have 3 and 3 and there
那里将是6个数字，那就是
would be 6 numbers in there and that's
两个男人是啊好吧我会停在那里
two men yeah ok ok I'm gonna stop there
正好在课程的一半但是
exactly halfway through the class but
好吧，我会在那里停下来
well I'm gonna stop there with a
我不知道的问题我不知道
question which I don't know I don't know
如果我敢发出另一个问题
if I dare send another question that
教授海报咖啡回答
professor poster coffee who answered
这一个完美但问题
this one perfectly but the question
你什么时候可以完成一个等级
would be when could you complete a rank
2矩阵什么位置可以你
2 matrix what what positions could you
填写并能够达到排名2
fill in and be able to reach rank 2 that
我不知道会不会有麻烦
would be trouble right I don't know
无论如何我们会去那里
where we would go with that but anyway
但这对我们来说是18或65的净值
but that's a net for us for 18 or 65
这是我自然而然的问题
that's the natural question when could I
我们排名1对我们而言非常特别
we rank 1 is super special for us and
等级2或等级
rank 2 or rank
是一般情况是的如此
would be the general case yeah so so
他们现在是很好的数学问题2
they're good math questions now topic 2
卷积所以第一个实验室
convolution so the first lab in the
当然正好有一个
course just happened to have a
卷积并使用该词等
convolution and use that word and so on
但我们没有，但我们没有连接
but we did not but we didn't connect
那个讲座所以现在我想
that with the lectures so now I'd like
谈论有关的卷积
to talk about convolutions which are
非常重要，他们是
extremely important and they are
在机器学习中很重要因为
important in machine learning because
他们给你一套重量
they give you a set of weights
连接它们是一种有效的方式-
connecting they're an efficient way to -
让我告诉你让我告诉你好
let me show you let me show you ok
所以卷积矩阵，这将是
so a convolution matrix and this will be
循环卷积配合确定和
a cyclic convolution mate ok and the
字循环的简写
word the shorthand for cyclic
卷积矩阵是循环的，所以
convolution matrix is circulant so what
是一个循环，我们称之为Ca
is a circulant we'll call it C a
circulant有一些羽毛球对角线
circulant has some mminton diagonals
这就是卷积意味着矩阵的意义
that's what convolution means matrix was
卷积意味着不变
convolution means constant
沿着每个对角线
down each diagonal
和循环意味着完整的循环
and cyclic means complete circle around
再次对角线对角线圈
again the diagonals diagonals circle
身边那么让我们告诉你我的意思是这样
around so let us show you what I mean so
四乘四比方说，所以它有一些
four by four let's say so it has some
进入这里有一个对角线是
entry to there's one diagonal here is
另一个对角线，所以现在我不断
another diagonal so now I have constant
对角线，但如果它将是一个
diagonals but if it's going to be a
循环矩阵，这是最好的
circulant matrix and this is the best
世界上的矩阵族
family of matrices in the world the
代数对这些来说太棒了
algebra is just terrific for these
矩阵，这就是为什么他们是
matrices and that's why they're the
这是信号处理的核心所以
heart of signal processing so so this is
一个恒定的对角矩阵，但事实并非如此
a constant diagonal matrix but it's not
还有一个对角圆圈的循环器
yet a circulant that diagonal circles
每个人都要完成
around to put to be completed every
对角线有四个条目，所以让我
diagonal has four entries here so let me
拿另一个说一个然后那个
take another one say one one then that
围绕a11和这个家伙
would circle around a11 and this guy
可能是0，这是一个循环矩阵
could be 0 there's a circulant matrix
你明白了你的条目
you understand then what the entry you
只需要四个数字说第一个
only need four numbers say the first
如果您指定了，则列
column if you if you prescribed the
然后是循环矩阵的第一列
first column of a circulant matrix then
你已经告诉了MATLAB所有的例子
you've told MATLAB for example all all
它需要知道你是否告诉它
it needs to know if you tell it one
列可以获取所有其他列
column it can get all the other columns
只是通过循环移位，第一个
just by cyclic shift there's the first
第2列015第二列是20
column 2 0 1 5 the second column is 2 0
15向下移动通过1的下一列是
1 5 shifted down by 1 the next column is
再次向下移动12015和
again shifted down by 1 2 0 1 5 and the
最后一栏是2015所以他们都是
last column is 2 0 1 5 so they're all
循环移位后的相同列
the same columns after a cyclic shift
所以这里的关键矩阵真的是一个
so the key matrix in this is really a
循环移位矩阵称零为零
cyclic shift matrix say zero one zero
零零零所以它只是说一个
zero zero zero so it just says one
非零对角线然后它是循环的
nonzero diagonal and then it's cyclic
你看，实际上这个矩阵C就是我
you see that in fact this matrix C is I
可以从P和P产生这个矩阵C.
can produce this matrix C from P and P
平方是的，我可以放入什么
squared yeah can I just put in what
P平方节拍我会写在这里
would P squared beats I'll write it here
在保持我们的同时保持这一点
without keeping that while keeping our
关注P所以如果我将那个矩阵平方化了什么
eye on P so if I square that matrix what
我会得到矩阵这是一个
matrix would I get so it's this is a
如果我再次换一个，则换一个
shift by one if I shift by one again
这又是P的倍增
that's multiplying again by P so that
会给我P平方
would give me P squared
什么是好的，所以
what what's in the what's in the okay so
现在发生了什么，它转移了两个我
what happens now it's shift by two I
想是这样所以这将是0010这
guess so so this will be 0 0 1 0 this
将是0001然后我是它的循环
will be 0 0 0 1 then I'm its cyclic
仍然如此，我把它放在那里
still so I'm put in the ones there and
然后只需填写零，所以P
then just fill in the zero ok so P
平方从2开始转移
squared shift by 2 you start out with
这一个是的，是的，是的确定好的
this one yep is that right yes yes ok ok
是的，让我们来做吧
yeah let's just let's just make it
将矢量X乘以X1X2X3
multiply a vector X naught X 1 X 2 X 3
它的作用是什么呢？
what it what it does is it puts it well
我已经在这里用2开始编号
I've started the numbering with 2 here X
2X3
2 X 3
x0和x1因此它将它移动了两次
x0 and x1 so it shifted it by two and
并周期性地得到了x2x3
and cyclically so the x2 x3 that got
从底部移开回到了
shifted off the bottom come back to the
顶部没关系，我想先展示一下
top okay what I want to show the first
财产是循环的，所以我想
property is of circulant so so suppose I
所以矩阵中有矩阵
have matrices see in the circular so
事实上1C倍d也是圆形的，从而
fact 1 C times D is also a circular so
如果我乘以循环矩阵，我得到
if I multiply circulant matrices I get
更多的循环矩阵和身份
more circulant matrices and the identity
是一个循环矩阵我有一点
is a circulant matrix I have a little
矩阵组是最好的小组
group of matrices the best little group
我可以将两个矩阵相乘
of matrices there is I can multiply two
小伙子们，我得到另一个
guys in the group and I get another one
在小组中为什么CD也是一个
in the group well why is CD also a
循环让我们看看能不能理解为什么
circulant let's see can we see why that
事实是真的我想这是我的方式
fact is true I guess here's my way to
看看它是一个循环矩阵让我放
look at it a circulant matrix let me put
它每个都把它放在一个循环矩阵
it put it here a circulant matrix every
循环矩阵是Cnaught次
circulant matrix is C naught times the
身份循环加C1次
identity circulant plus C 1 times the
单班加C加倍的2倍
single shift plus C 2 times the double
换班加C三倍班次
shift plus C 3 times the triple shift
那就是放C的方法
that that's what it takes to put C
那些没有C1C2和C3
naught C 1 C 2 and C 3 on those
对角线C很明显就是上了
diagonals C naught is obviously on the
主对角线C1P记住P是什么
main diagonal C 1 P remember what P is
将Cone放在下一个对角线上
that puts C one on the next diagonal
然后C2P平方，当我对此
then C 2 P squared when i square this
我已经换了一个所以它会放
I've shifted by one more so it will put
C2即将死亡
C 2 on that dying
最后c3会进入那些
and finally c3 would go in those
因此每个循环矩阵都是一个
positions so every circulant matrix is a
P中的多项式在单个移位中
polynomial in P in a single shift this
这是一个转变的任何组合
is any combination of shifts this is a
单班，这是一个双重转变
single shift that's a double shift
这是一个零转换
that's a triple shift that's a zero
转移，如果我采取组合，我得到我
shift and if I take combinations i get i
得到一个循环矩阵所以我现在可以
get a circulant matrix so so now I can
看看为什么CD也是一个循环因素
see why CD is also a circulant because
这是P中的多项式，这是一个
this is a polynomial in P and this is a
P中的多项式和乘法时的多项式
polynomial in P and when I multiply
那些我在P中得到一个多项式
those together I get a polynomial in P
但通常如果我乘以三度
but usually if I multiply a third degree
多项式由我们另外三度
polynomial by us another third degree
多项式所以说我正在看四
polynomial so say I'm looking at four by
四个循环矩阵，所以这将是
four circulant matrices so this would be
多项式PNP三度三度
a polynomial P NP a third degree three
这将是多项式度数3
and this would be a polynomial degree 3
所以这会给我一个多项式
so that would give me a polynomial of
6级，但我不希望那样
degree 6 but I don't want that that's
不知怎的，我必须定义乘法
somehow I have to define multiplication
所以我希望这是这些程度
so that I want this to be degree these
都应该是4乘4矩阵
are all supposed to be 4 by 4 matrices
就像那个
just like that one
这是身份的两倍加上5P加
that's twice the identity plus 5 P plus
1P平方加0P立方并假设我
1 P squared plus 0 P cubed and suppose I
然后，我将再次得到的广场
square that then again I'm going to get
循环矩阵，我不想要它
a circulant matrix and I don't want it
升到7级我想让你知道我
to go up to degree 7 I want you know I
只是想在我的多项式四个学期
just want four terms in my polynomial
我只想要主要的对角线
I just want the main diagonal in the
接下来的三个对角线然后循环
next three diagonals and then cyclic
骑自行车绕完成矩阵，
cycling around completes the matrix so
为什么我怎么得到哈哈
why what's how do I get ha ha
如何获得学位三分
how to get degree threes that's the
问题就可以你刚才告诉我
question then can you just tell me the
回答所以我倍增是的让我们
answer so I'm multiplying yeah let's
只是做一个例子，所以我看到的不是C1
just do an example so I've seen not C 1
pc2P平方C3P立方次D.
p c 2 P squared C 3 P cubed times D
没有加P1P加D2P平方和
naught plus P 1 P plus D 2 P squared and
D3P立方因此P为P而P为4
D 3 P cubed so that's P is this P is 4
通过4轮循环好转，我正在写
by 4 circular shift okay and I'm writing
所述4乘4矩阵这种方式，这是本
the 4 by 4 matrix that way this is this
应该是当然的身份好了，
should be the identity of course okay so
当我繁衍那些家伙为什么我不这样做
when I multiply those guys why do I not
拿到学位6，为什么我这是为什么
get degree 6 why am i why is that
产品如P立方倍P立方C3P.
product like P cubed times P cubed C 3 P
立方体NT3P立方体，给我C3D3
cubed NT 3 P cube that gives me C 3 D 3
P到6次方
P to the 6th power
怎么了我该怎么办是的
so what's up what do I do yeah yes
那是周期性部分的关键
that's the key that's the periodic part
P到4等于身份谢谢你
P to the 4 equal the identity thank ya
所以P到第六项真的是P
so the P to the sixth term is really a P
平方项P到第五项是
squared term the P to the fifth term is
真的是P到P到第四学期
really a P term the P to the fourth term
真的是0到0的P所以是的
is really a P to the 0 term so yeah so
我只是在做我正在做的事情
I'm I'm just doing I'm doing what I'm
做循环卷积实际上让我
doing cyclic convolution actually let me
只是说当我倍增的时候
just say when I'm multiplying yeah
所以我现在告诉你我能做什么
so I'm now I'm telling you what I can
首先告诉你卷积是什么和
first tell you what convolution is and
那么什么循环卷积是这
then what cyclic convolution is and this
是真的听这个，因为它是
is real listen up to this because it's
知道这是件好事
it's a good thing to know
是的首先是卷积
yeah so first of all convolution
所以我们假设我想接受
so we suppose I want to take the
这是三个一二的卷积
convolution of three one two that's
通常是卷积的符号
often the symbol for convolution with
四个六个一个没关系，那怎么办我怎么样
four six one okay so how do i how what
这是否意味着我有一个矢量
does that mean I've got a vector so
什么对我有什么好处隐藏在那里
what's high for me what's hiding there
是多项式三加X加二
is is polynomials three plus X plus two
x平方乘以4加6x加1x
x squared times four plus 6x plus one x
平方，我只是将它们相乘
squared and I just multiply them out and
我得到五，所以我得到3次4给我一个
I get five so I get 3 times 4 gives me a
123次6x是18x但我也有
12 3 times 6x is 18x but I've also got
从这里开始4倍，所以我得到22X所以我只是
4x from here so I've got 22 X so I just
做多项式的乘法
do that multiplication of polynomials
和我在做什么是卷积
and what I'm doing is convolution with
向量，这是你写的方式
the vectors and here's the way you wrote
它在一年级
it in in first grade
好的，所以这里的一年级还好
okay so here's first grade okay
2128这是你还没学会的
212 8 this is you haven't learned to
随身携带，所以12在那里12
carry yeah so 12 goes in there as 12
然后1是461和3是12183然后
then 1 is 4 6 1 & 3 is 12 18 3 and then
你加起来所以你有2131722和12
you add up so you have 2 13 17 22 and 12
让我这样，这就是答案
let me just so so that that's the answer
还有，他们的卷积我想我
there that their convolution I guess I
必须从是啊123次4
have to take it from yeah 12 3 times 4
现在给了12次3次6次加1次4次
gave 12 now 3 times 6 plus 1 times 4
那是22
that's the 22
哦，是的，我们已经开始了，但现在
oh yeah we already started here but now
那之后是什么，为什么我说七
what's after that 17 why did I say seven
牙齿哦八加六加三
teeth oh eight plus six plus three
谢谢
Thanks
十七，然后十二加一
seventeen and then twelve plus one
十三，然后-那是非循环的
thirteen and then - that's non-cyclic so
如果我想要它，那就是卷积哦
that's convolution oh if I if I want it
非循环我不放圆圈
to be non-cyclic I don't put a circle in
所以这是普通人的象征
so that's a symbol for ordinary
如果您执行MATLAB命令，则进行卷积
convolution if you do the MATLAB command
如果你给它卷积的CoNV
Co NV for convolution if you gave it
那些矢量它会给你五个
those vectors it would give you five a
结果有五个组件的向量
vector with five components as a result
但是如果你现在让我做六个像
but if you now let me make it six like
好的，那么现在会发生什么
okay so what's going to happen now when
我让它循环，所以这代表12
I make it cyclic so this represents 12
22P17P平方13P立方和什么
22 P 17 P squared 13 P cubed and what
如果我正在做的话，那就是13P立方体
happens what's 13 P cubed if I'm doing
如果n是3而我正在做3乘3矩阵
if n is 3 and I'm doing 3 by 3 matrices
然后13P立方体与13右P相同
then 13 P cube is the same as 13 right P
立方体是我所以13将回到那里
cube is I so the 13 will go back there
2将是P4，它会去
and the 2 will be P 4th and it'll go
回到P所以现在用卷积
back as P so so the now with convolution
循环卷积给出12和132522
cyclic convolution gives 12 and 13 25 22
和224和17好吧所以我得到了我
and 224 and the 17 okay so I've get I'm
我只是回到长度为3的向量
getting back a vector of length 3 I just
如果我有3乘3，我想做什么
as I want to do if I have a 3 by 3
矩阵卷积循环循环
matrix convolution cyclic circulant
矩阵是那三个对角线和
matrix were those three diagonals and
这三个对角线，我想要的
these three diagonals and I want the
回答是三个矩阵3
answer to be a three by three matrix
这些对角线是如此再次矩阵
were these diagonals so again matrix
乘法
multiplication
循环矩阵完全对应
circulant matrices corresponds exactly
周期性地乘以多项式
to multiplying polynomials cyclically
那是循环卷积然后
and that's cyclic convolution and then
只有一个小技巧，看看是否
there's just one little trick to see if
你相信我的数字是正确的
you've got the numbers right I believe
如果3加1，那应该是真的
that it should be true that if 3 plus 1
加2是64加6加1是11和我
plus 2 is 6 4 plus 6 plus 1 is 11 and I
相信那些应该添加到
believe that those should add to add to
什么我希望他们添加266
what what do I hope that they add 266
这样做我有点紧张
I'm a little nervous about doing it but
我想我们可以，所以4950966检查
I think we can yeah so 49 50 966 check
是的所以数字是总和
yeah so the the digits the sum of the
一个因子的数字乘以总和
digits of one factor multiplies the sum
的另一个因素的数字
of the digits of the other factor to
给出数字的总和
give the sum of the digits in the
卷积，这是真的
convolution and that would be true
我们是否做了循环
whether we doing cyclic which is
把13和管子带回来或
bringing the 13 and the tube back in or
不循环我们有五个
not cyclic where where we have five
数字是的，所以这实际上是一个
numbers yeah so that's that's actually a
检查一点，我不知道是否
check that little that I don't know if
你曾经想到过这一点
you've ever thought about that in second
年级
grade
乘以这些数字乘以
multiplying these numbers multiplying
这个数字被这个数字和获取
that number by that number and getting
一些答案，可能是一半
some answer which probably half the
类没有得到正确的那么五年级
class did not get right then 5th grade
他们有点得到它但是
they've they're kind of getting it but
如果他们知道支票就可以了
if they knew a check so they could have
刚添加这些数字以获得11
just added these numbers to get 11 added
这些数字得到6乘以那些
these numbers to get 6 multiplied those
获得66并检查那些
to get 66 and check that that those
添加266我从来没有发生在我身上
added 266 I'd never had occurred to me
我承认和二年级都没有
I admit and second grade neither but
这是一件好事，现在你已经知道你
it's a good thing now you know now you
可以通过二年级，所以这是
can pass second grade okay so so this is
循环卷积的图片和我
the picture for cyclic convolution and I
还剩下几分钟告诉你
just have a few minutes left to tell you
关于特征值和特征向量
about the eigenvalues and eigenvectors
这些矩阵所以你能告诉我们什么
of these matrices so what can you tell
我关于特征值，我说的
me about the eigenvalues and i say the
特征向量我有一个矩阵p发生
eigenvectors i have a matrix p happens
作为一个排列矩阵，但它是一个
to be a permutation matrix but it's a
矩阵然后我把这个多项式
matrix then I take this polynomial in
什么可以告诉我什么矩阵
the matrix what can you tell me about
这个矩阵的特征向量C所以我
the eigenvectors of this matrix C so I
写我的C看起来像
have write my C looks like looks like
那个，我问你的
that and I'm asking you for the
那个特征向量，我就是这么说的
eigenvectors of that and I'm saying that
这是一个是多项式的和
that is a is a sum of is a polynomial
P的权力总和实际上是这样的
sum of powers of P like so in fact
这里的数字刚刚从对角线上掉下来
numbers here just come off the diagonals
那么特征向量呢？
so what about the eigenvectors well that
是一个特征向量，它是真正的向量
is an eigenvector that's true the vector
所有的人将与特征向量
of all ones will be an eigenvector with
什么特征值实际是啊是啊所以我
what eigenvalue actually yeah yeah so I
我想让你看到的是
what I wanted to want you to see is the
C的特征向量与
eigenvectors of C are the same as the
如果我有一个P的特征向量
eigenvectors of P if I have an
p的特征向量也是一个
eigenvector of p that's also an
p平方和P立方的特征向量
eigenvector of p squared and P cubed and
P的特征向量的组合
a combination so eigenvectors of P are
座位的特征向量
eigenvectors of seats
那么问题是什么呢
so then the question is what are the
P的特征向量你明白我的意思
eigenvectors of P you see what I mean
它不是真的没关系
that it doesn't it didn't really matter
如果我正在寻找特征向量的东西
if I'm looking for eigenvectors what
那些数字是重点
those numbers were the point is that
这些数字在对角线上是恒定的
those numbers were constant on diagonals
因此他们我拥有它
and that they therefore they I have it's
由一个内置的矩阵P构建而成
built out of one matrix P built out of
一个矩阵P所以我所要做的就是
one matrix P so if all I have to do is
P是的的特征向量所以这是
the eigenvectors of P yep so that's the
这里的最后一步是什么
final step here what are the
p的特征向量和特征值
eigenvectors and eigenvalues of p so
特征向量p的特征值等于11
eigenvectors eigenvalues for p equal 1 1
1和1说，否则0所以有人
1 and 1 say and otherwise 0 so somebody
提到了1111的向量
mentioned that the vector of 1 1 1 1
这是一个特征向量，因为如果我
that that is an eigenvector because if I
做那个乘法它改变了这一点
do that multiplication it shifts this
矢量向下和循环周围但是
vector down and cyclically around but
这只是带回相同的矢量
that just brings back the same vector so
lambda是1，这是一个特征向量
lambda is 1 and that's an eigenvector
特征值为1，但这是4乘4
with eigenvalue 1 but this is a 4 by 4
矩阵
matrix
哦，现在你猜1个减1负
oh now you're guessing 1 minus 1 1 minus
1有趣的好吧告诉我一个
1 interesting well right tell me an
如果你想要兄弟，那么特征向量4减去1
eigenvector 4 minus 1 if you want to bro
只是在那里交替标志让我
just alternating signs there so let me
让我做倍增时间1
let me do that multiplication times 1
减11减去1我当然没有
minus 1 1 minus 1 of course I don't have
做这个乘法我只是去
to do this multiplication I'm just going
转移这个，所以我要转移它
to shift this so I'm going to shift that
下
down
1减11并循环周围和
1 minus 1 1 and cyclically around and
现在它的特征值是什么
now what's the eigenvalue it is an
特征向量和特征值是什么
eigenvector and what's the eigenvalue
这使得该矢量的多个
that makes what multiple of that vector
给出了这个向量减去1的结果
gives that gives that vector minus 1 so
这是一个好主意，但剩下的
that was a good idea but the rest of
你说的是一个坏主意，因为
what you said was was a bad idea because
我们必须看下一个特征向量
we've got to look the next eigen vectors
我们必须在别的地方
are got to be somewhere else we've just
有一个特征值出现在1那里，
got one eigenvalue there on 1 there and
我们还没有得到其他两个还等什么
we haven't got the other two so what are
另外两个特征值
the other two eigenvalues of this
排列矩阵一个是正​​确的
permutation matrix one that's right
我们在一个循环的世界画一个圆圈
we're in a circulant world draw a circle
所以特征向量是四个根
so the eigenvectors are the four roots
一个复合体，一个又一个
of one complex so one and minus one
你有这些是lambda，但是
you've got these are the lambdas but the
其他的是我和我是的，为什么
other ones are i and- i yeah yep why
不让我离开，直到因为时间到让
don't I leave until since time's up let
我离开星期五的特征值
me leave until Friday the eigen values
和一般的特征向量
and eigen vectors for in general for
任意大小，但这是一张图片
arbitrary size but that's a picture of
特征我们接近于本征
the eigen we're close to the eigen
每个人的向量和特征值
vectors and eigen values of every all
循环具有相同的特征向量
circulant have the same eigen vectors
所有的循环都有特征向量
all circulant have that eigenvector also
所有循环都有四个四分之一
four by four all circulant have that
特征向量四乘四，我们会发现
eigenvector four by four and we'll find
另外两个好，所以我会见到你
the other two okay so I'll see you
周五为那些和卷积
Friday for those and the convolution
rule which is the most important rule in
规则这是最重要的规则
信号处理好的谢谢
signal processing okay thanks